Guide to the Peter Drucker Oral History Collection OH.037
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Peter Drucker Oral History Collection
1986-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Drucker, Peter
OH.037
1.73 Linear Feet in 2 folders in a shared manuscript box, a CD box, and 20 audiocassettes in a shared cassette box.
20 audiocassettes
33 CDs
664 kilobytes in 2 documents
Peter Drucker is an activist, historian, and writer specializing in U.S. and international politics for over twenty years. The Peter Drucker Oral History Collection (dated 1986-1989) consists of eight interviews conducted by Drucker between 1986-1989. The interviews were used in Drucker's 1994 book, Max Shachtman and His Left: A Socialist's Odyssey through the American Century.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Peter Drucker in circa 1994. The accession number associated with this gift is 1950.081.
Arrangement
The interviews are arranged alphabetically by last name.
Biographical Note
Peter Drucker is an activist, historian, and writer specializing in U.S. and international politics for over twenty years. He has written for publications such as the Guardian, International Viewpoint, Shmate and Gay Community News. He is currently an editor of the socialist journal Against the Current.
In 1994, Peter Drucker published the first full-length biography of Max Shachtman, a key figure in the 1960s civil rights, labor and peace movements. Max Shachtman and His Left: A Socialist's Odyssey through the American Century draws on previously untapped archives and interviews to provide a comprehensive study of an important civil rights figure.
Scope and Contents
The Peter Drucker Oral History Collection (dated 1986-1989) consists of eight interviews conducted by Drucker between 1986-1989. The interviews were used in Drucker's 1994 book, Max Shachtman and His Left: A Socialist's Odyssey through the American Century. The collection has been digitized and access CDs are available for researcher use.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Oral history.; Socialism -- United States.; Biography (genre); Civil rights workers.; Communism -- United States.; Shachtman, Max, 1903-1972
- Benson, Herman, April 6, 1989
  Scope and Contents
  An electronic transcript is available.
  - Transcript (Box Shared Tamiment 188, Folder 6)
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 1-4)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 097, Audiocassette 1A-C)
- Draper, Hal, February 13, 1989
  - Transcript (Box Shared Tamiment 188, Folder 7)
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 1-9)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 097, Audiocassette 2A-E)
- Geier, Joel -- Transcript, April 17, 1989; TW_OH_037_ER_1
- Geltman, Emanuel, March 22, 1989; cuid43108
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 1-2)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 097, Audiocassette 4A)
- Glotzer, Abraham, March 24, March 28, and April 4, 1989
  Cassette tape #5D is missing. Therefore the digitized content reflects only tapes A,B,C, and E.
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 1-8)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 097, Audiocassette 5A-C, 5E)
- Haskell, Gordon, July 8, 1989
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 097, Audiocassette 6A)
  - Transcript, TW_OH_037_ER_2
- Kahn, Thomas, April 7, 1989
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 1-3)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 097, Audiocassette 7A-C)
- Lewitt, Morris, February 3, 1990
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 1-2)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 097, Audiocassette 8)
- Seidlitz, Leo, January 6 and February 7, 1989
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 1-4)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 097, Audiocassette 9A-B)